<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--Pedia-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Tlingit also known as "People of the Tides" and are a Native Amercian people that inhabit a vast amount of area on the Southeastern coast and coastal islands of Alaska. The Tlingit's culture has been molded by the conditions of the Alaskan area. The coast of Alaska is covered with mountains. The climate is temperate and humid. The forests are populated with animal life and seas are bountiful as well. The Tlingit Indians originally survived by fishing, hunting, and gathering, but later adapted to a more sedentary way of life constructing and erecting  grand monuments such as Totem Poles that still stand the test of time today.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Geography and Climate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Alaska is a huge land mass that contains many different environments ranging from the frigid streams and tundra above the Arctic circle to the windy islands of the Aleutians to the mild rainy weather of southeast Alaska. Alaska consists of over 533,000 square miles, with a coastline as long that of the rest of the continental United States. The southern end of the Alaska coastline, a region known as Southeast Alaska, is home to the primary Tlingit (pronounced "klingit") communities. Tlingit communities are located from just south of Ketchikan and are scattered northward across islands and mainland as far as the Icy Bay area. Tlingit people also occupy some inland area on the Canadian side of the border in British Columbia and the Yukon Territory. The mainland Tlingit of Alaska occupy a range of mountains from 50 to 100 miles inland. The northern portion of Tlingit country is glacial with the majesty of the Fairweather and Saint Elias mountains overlooking the northern shores of the Gulf of Alaska. Fjords, mountains that dive into the sea, islands, and ancient trees make up most of this wet country that is part of one of the largest temperate rain forests in the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Origins of the Tlingit</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The name Tlingit essentially means human beings. The word was originally used simply to distinguish a human being from an animal, since Tlingits believed that there was little difference between humans and animals. Over time the word came to be a national name. Tlingit legends speak of migrations into the area from several possible directions, either from the north as a possible result of the Bering Sea land bridge, or from the southwest, after a maritime journey from the Polynesian islands across the Pacific. It is speculated that human occupation of southeast Alaska occurred 11,000 years ago by Tlingit people. Haida people, with whom the Tlingit have frequent interaction, have only been in the area about 200 years, and the Tsimpsian migrated only recently from the Canadian interior mainland. They have no linguistic relationship to any other language except for a vague similarity to the Athabaskan language. They also share some cultural similarity with the Athabaskan, with whom the Tlingit have interacted and traded for centuries. There may also be a connection between the Haida and the Tlingit, but this issue is debated. Essentially, the origin of the Tlingit is unknown.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The Kwan System</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Tlingit people are grouped and divided into units called kwan. Some anthropological accounts estimate that 15 to 20 kwan existed at the time of European contact. A kwan was a group of people who lived in a mutual area, shared residence, intermarried, and lived in peace. Communities containing a Tlingit population may be called the Sitkakwan, the Taku-kwan, or the Heenya-kwan, depending on their social ties and/or location. Most of the urban communities of Southeast Alaska occupy the sites of many of the traditional kwan communities. Before the arrival of explorers and settlers, groups of Tlingit people would travel by canoe through treacherous waters for hundreds of miles to engage in war, attend ceremonies, trade, or marry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_5">
			<Text>European Contact</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Through trade with other tribes as far south as the Olympic Peninsula and even northern California, the Tlingit people had established sophisticated skills. In the mid-1700s, the Spaniards and the British, attracted by the fur trade, penetrated the Northwest via the Juan de Fuca Islands (in the Nootka Sound area). The Russians, also in search of furs, invaded the Aleutian Islands and moved throughout the southwestern coast of Alaska toward Tlingit country. The Tlingit traders may have heard stories of these strangers coming but took little heed. Europeans arrived in Tlingit country for the first time in 1741, when Russian explorer Aleksey Chirikov sent a boatload of men to land for water near the modern site of Sitka. When the group did not return for several days, he sent another boat of men to shore; they also did not return. Thereafter, contact with Tlingit people was limited until well into the 1800s.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_6">
			<Text>The Battle for Sitka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Russian invaders subdued the Aleut people, and moving southward, began their occupation of Tlingit country. Having monopolized trade routes in any direction from or to Southeast Alaska, the Tlingit people engaged in somewhat friendly but profitable trading with the newcomers until the Russians became more aggressive in their attempts to colonize and control trade routes. In 1802 Chief Katlian of the Kiksadi Tlingit of the Sitka area successfully led his warriors against the Russians, who had set up a fort in Sitka with the limited permission of the Tlingit. Eventually the Russians recaptured Sitka and maintained a base they called New Archangel, but they had little contact with the Sitka clans. For years the Tlingit resisted occupation and the use of their trade routes by outsiders. In 1854 a Chilkat Tlingit war party travelled hundreds of miles into the interior and destroyed a Hudson Bay Company post in the Yukon Valley.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_7">
			<Text>The Land Claims Period</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_7">
			<Text>The Treaty of Cession (1867) referred to indigenous people of Alaska as "uncivilized tribes." Such designation in legislation and other agreements caused Alaska Natives to be subject to the same regulations and policies as American Indians in the United States. The 1885 Major Crimes Act, which was intended to strip tribes of their right to deal with criminal matters according to traditional customs. By the turn of the century, the Tlingit people were threatened politically, territorially, culturally, and socially. In response, the Tlingit people organized the Alaska Native Brotherhood (ANB). The ANB was founded in Sitka in 1912 by nine Tlingit and one Tsimpsian. The ANB's goals were to gain equality for the Native people of Southeast Alaska and to obtain for them the same citizenship and education rights as non-Natives.  In 1959—the same year that Alaska was admitted as a state—the Court of Claims decided in favor of the Tlingit and Haida for payment of land that was taken from them. The Tlingit-Haida land claims involved 16 million acres without a defined monetary value; an actual settlement took years to conclude. In 1971, the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) was passed, which called for the settlement of all claims against the United States and the state of Alaska that are based on aboriginal right, title, use, or occupancy of land or water areas in Alaska.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Modern Times</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_TEXT_8">
			<Text>As Americans and Christian missionaries forced their culture upon the Tlingit people, many attempted to fight inequality and prejudice. In 1945, Tlingit member Elizabeth Peratrovitch pled for the passage of an anti-discrimination bill, which eventually was made into law. The State of Alaska then recognized February eighth as an annual celebration day in her honor. Nowadays, ANSCA corporations have substantial lobbying power in the area, representing 16,000 Tlingit and Haida people. A large population have jobs in the logging, forestry, fishing, and tourism industries, while their support of higher education has led to many with occupations such as healthcare workers, lawyers, and educators. Most of these people have relocated to more populous areas of southeast Alaska for more abundant employment opportunities. Sealaska and other ANSCA corporations provide corporate and managerial positions to some Tlingit people. While many Tlingit have adapted to a modernized lifestyle, some are still attempting to subsist off of the Alaskan land, despite growing fishing and logging industries nearby.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_FACTOID_HEADING">
			<Text>Tlingit Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_CL_TLINGIT_FACTOID_TEXT">
			<Text>The seventh Sheiyksh, Charlie Jones, was arrested 1922 for voting, because Native Americans were not automatically considered U.S. citizens at that time. During his trial, he was represented by the famous Tlingit attorney William Paul. Jones was acquitted and the Tlingit were given the right to vote in 1924.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Leader-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Sheiyksh I was the first of the Sheiyksh leaders of the Tlingit. Growing up an orphan, he was adopted by the leader of the clan. After the clan leader's death, Gush X'een rallied his forces and pushed back rivals tribes who hoped to take their land. After the fight, Gush X'een took the name of his enemy, Sheiyksh, which would become the leadership title among the Tlingit people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				Gush X'een was born as Jooná'w, in the village of Ch'aal'in, but was left an orphan at a young age. The clan's leader, S'nook, took a liking to the young Gush X'een and adopted him as a nephew. When S'nook died, Gush X'een took over as leader of the clan.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_HEADING_3">
			<Text>War with Rivals</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_TEXT_3">
			<Text>
				Gush X'een would later refuse the Nisga'a and Tsimshian people access to the Stikine river for fishing. The Tsimshian leader Wiisheyksh warned Gush X'een that they would take the river by force, and so, both sides prepared for war. Gush X'een set his forces up at the mouth of the river, with a small faction by the base of the cliffs near the mouth of the river, hiding the majority of his troops by the nearby islands. Having a force of over 100 war canoes, and seeing only a small force, Wiisheyksh disembarked and taunted Gush X'een. At this point, Gush X'een called his forces from from the islands, turning his seemingly small force into an overwhelming one.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Wiisheyksh would then surrender. Not wanting to be Gush X'een's slave, Wiisheyksh would present his prized killer whale headdress to Gush X'een. Gush X'een placed the headdress upon his head and said,“Not only do I take your hat, I take your name as well.” Wiisheyksh became a Tlingit name and was shortened to Sheiyksh.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Legacy and successors</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_TEXT_4">
			<Text>
				After Gush X'een's death, the title of Sheiyksh passed to his sister's oldest son, Gookshí, who became the second Sheiyksh. Since then there have been nine people to have the title of Sheiyksh, the title often passing from uncle to nephew, with the last person to hold it, Johnathan DeWitt, dying in 2007.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_LIVED">
			<Text>Unknown</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_NAME">
			<Text>Sheiyksh I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Gush X'een</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_CL_SHAKES_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Leader of the Tlingit</Text>
		</Row>

	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>