<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 5/8/2021 2:00:39 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- Murri Dreaming -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_BURRUGUU_NGAYI_LI">
			<Text>Burruguu-ngayi-li</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_BURRUGUU_NGAYI_LI_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				The Emu in the Sky[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				The Coalsack is a dark cloud just below the Southern Cross. For many Aboriginal people across Australia, this is the head of the Emu in the Sky, which stretches from the Southern Cross along the dust lanes of the Milky Way to the constellation Scorpius. Unlike non-Aboriginal people, the Kamilaroi and their neighbours see the dark spaces (dust lanes) of the Milky Way, rather than the stars, as important, because this is where the Emu in the Sky is seen. The Kamilaroi call the Emu Gawarrgay, rather than Dhinawan, which is the name for the emu bird.[NEWLINE]
				For the Kamilaroi and their neighbours, the Emu in the Sky had important ceremonial and resource meaning. At different times of the year, the Emu may or not be seen, or may be seen differently, due to the tilt of the Earth and the seasons, when the Milky Way’s position in the sky changes.[NEWLINE]
				The Emu first becomes visible as the Milky Way rises in the evening in April and May, and at this time the Emu appears to be running.  The Kamilaroi see this as when the emus on Earth are breeding, and the female is chasing the male. This also means that the female emu will be laying eggs, so it is time to start collecting emu eggs for food.[NEWLINE]
				In June and July the male Emu is sitting on the nest, brooding the chicks, so it is still time to collect eggs.[NEWLINE]
				Come  August, everyone has been in their winter camp, and it is time to start planning ceremonies for the summer, particularly the bora, the male initiation ceremony. Because the male emus care for the chicks, there is a connection with the bora, where the men care for the young men, so the Emu in the Sky is vertical over the South, which is the direction that the bora site, which is two circles connected by a path, is oriented. The Emu can also look like two eggs, which is a sign that the eggs are hatching, and should no longer be collected.[NEWLINE]
				Later in the year, the Milky Way and the Emu dip close to the Earth, and the Emu is thought to be sitting in a waterhole, which is full from the spring rain.  The Emu is also thought to be a  featherless emu  which  travels  to  waterholes  and  looks  after  everything  that  lives  there. The Euahlayi also call this Emu ngurran.gali, which translates to “emu in water”.[NEWLINE]
				After the Emu in the Sky is no longer seen during summer, the Kamilaroi and Euahlayi say that the Emu has travelled to Earth, and is seen as the black emu bird, which is very rare.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				From “Star Stories of the Dreaming: An Education Guide”
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Eora Dreaming -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_GUNYALUNGALUNG">
			<Text>Gunyalungalung</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_GUNYALUNGALUNG_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				The eel shows up frequently in Eora and Dharug Dreaming stories. Burramattagal (aka. Parramatta) itself means place of the eels and various instances of rock art around the harbour contains images of eels.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Story of Boora Birra and the Great Eel[NEWLINE]
				As told by Dharwal elder F. Bodkin[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				A long time ago, when there was no evil in this land, the sea was further to the east than it is today, and the place called Boora Birra stood high in the deep valley which it guarded. This valley was the home of the Parra Doowee, the Eel Dreaming Spirit. Now Boora Birra was a special place for women, who, when needed, carried out the ceremony called Butowee there. Every child, when they reached a certain age, was taken to the Boora Birra where they were taught certain things, and received protection from any evil spirits which could enter them and cause them to do evil things.[NEWLINE]
				Because the land between the deep valleys and the sea shore was flat and easy walking, with plenty of food, the people became fat, lazy and forgetful. The men no longer honoured the spirits of the animals they hunted and killed, and they wasted much of their prey, eating only the parts they liked most and leaving the remainder to rot away. And the women no longer taught their children the ways of The People, they no longer paid their respects to the Earth Mother, or gave thanks for the food they received so easily.[NEWLINE]
				The children grew to manhood and womanhood without being taught the laws, and why it is necessary to obey those laws. They formed themselves into bands that roamed the flatlands, destroying the gunyas of the old, stealing fishing spears and hunting weapons, and using them to fight the members of other bands.[NEWLINE]
				The People heard them coming and would conceal themselves high upon the Boora Birra. From this vantage point they watched with trepidation as one band approached the home of the Great Eel guarded by the old warrior, Kamarai. Kamarai heard the noise of an approaching group, and went to welcome his visitors. But he was quickly surrounded by the lawless ones who laughed at his clumsy actions as he tried to avoid the jabbing of their spears.[NEWLINE]
				Bleeding from many wounds, the old man fell to the ground. In a deep pool in the river the Great Eel heard the commotion and heard the cries of help from his old friend. It swam up to the surface of the pool. The lawless ones saw the Great Eel and threw their spears at him in fear as it pulled itself up out of the water. Its great body moved towards its old friend as the last spear of the lawless ones struck its tail.[NEWLINE]
				When it saw that Kamarai had died of his wounds, it cried out in grief and pain, and struck the ground with its great tail, dislodging the spear. The Earth began to shake violently, and a great chasm opened up in the ground, following the fleeing lawless ones and swallowing them as they fled towards the flatlands. Then a storm came in from the sea, and the waves crashed across the flatlands until they reached the cliffs that marked the beginning of the highlands.[NEWLINE]
				“Let this be a warning,” The Great Eel said. “The laws of This Land must be obeyed, and the proper ceremonies must be carried out in the proper manner. It turned to look at the Boora Birra, slowly being engulfed by the waves. “And the Boora Birra will now be a place where the sea creatures take their children to teach them the laws of The Sea. But you may visit, safely from time to time, so that you will remember why the laws must be passed on to the young. And because good lessons can always be learned from evil, this place will be safe for The People, to hunt and to fish, and live and teach the laws.”[NEWLINE]
				The Great Eel slipped silently into the water, and with a splash of its tail disappeared beneath the waves. The People watched the waves, hoping for a glimpse of the Great Eel as it made its way to its new home. One of the children, a young boy, went to the water’s edge, then looked back at his mother and smiled. And spoke in a voice that was not his: “Until we forget again,” he said. “Until we forget again.”
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Ngarrindjeri Dreaming -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KALDOWINYERI">
			<Text>Kaldowinyeri</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_KALDOWINYERI_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				Ngurunderi and Pondi[NEWLINE]As told in the Ngarrindjeri Nation Yarluwar-Ruwe (Sea Country) Plan[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				A long, long time ago Ngurunderi, the Spiritual Ancestor chased Pondi, the giant Murray Cod, from the junction where the Darling and Murrundi (River Murray) meet. Back then, the River Murray was just a small stream and Pondi had nowhere to go. As Ngurunderi chased him in his bark canoe he went ploughing and crashing through the land and his huge body and tail created the mighty River Murray.  When Ngurunderi and his brother-in-law Nepele caught Pondi at the place where the fresh and salt water meet, they cut him up into many pieces, which became the fresh and salt water fish for the Ngarrindjeri people. To the last piece Ngurunderi said, “you keep being a Pondi (Murray Cod)”[NEWLINE]
				As Ngurunderi travelled throughout Ngarrindjeri Country, he created landforms, waterways and life. He gave to his people the stories, meanings and laws associated with our lands and waters of his creation. He gave each Lakalinyeri (clan) their identity to their Ruwe (country) and their Ngarjtis (animals,birds, fish and plants) - who are friends. Ngurunderi taught them how to hunt and gather foods from the lands and waters. He taught Ngarrindjeri, don't be greedy, don't take any more than what you need, and share with one another. Ngurunderi also warned them that if they don't share, they will be punished.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Wiradjuri Dreaming -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_MURAYMIN">
			<Text>Muraymin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_MURAYMIN_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				Baiame (variously spelt) is an ancestor of the Wiradjuri, Kamilaroi, Eora, and various other surrounding nations. He is credited with the creation of everything, the land, sky, rivers, mountains, life, songs, bora, etc. (something that has led some to believe he had been created by Christian missionaries, but he seems to have existed prior to them coming to Australia) and has various Dreaming stories associated with him (eg. Kengal, Kengal was created by Baiame when he left his dingo companions here to wait for his return, eventually they turned into Kengal.)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				‘Mother, what is that one sea,[NEWLINE]
				Sometimes blue or green or yellow?’[NEWLINE]
				‘That’s Biami’s waterhole.[NEWLINE]
				He big fellow.’[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				‘Mother, what make sunset fire,[NEWLINE]
				Every night the big red glare?’[NEWLINE]
				‘Biami’s gunya out that way,[NEWLINE]
				That his camp fre over there.’[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				‘How come great wide river here,[NEWLINE]
				Where we swim and fish with spear?’[NEWLINE]
				‘Biami dug him.[NEWLINE]
				You see big hills all about?[NEWLINE]
				They stuff that he shuck out.’[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Poem by Oodgeroo Noonuccal
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Kulin Dreaming -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_MURRUP_BIIK">
			<Text>Murrup Biik</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_MURRUP_BIIK_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				Bunjil, the wedge-tailed eagle, and Waa, the crow, (both variously spelt) are two of the main ancestors of the groups that made up the Kulin, they feature in many stories about the creation of the land and its laws. Two such follow[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Bunjil and the Filling of the Bay[NEWLINE]Boon Wurrung Country. As told by Aunty Carolyn Briggs[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				One day, many years ago, there came a time of chaos and crisis. The Boon Wurrung and the other Kulin nations were in conflict. They argued and fought. They neglected their biik (land). The native murnong (yam daisy) was neglected. The animals were over killed and not always eaten. The gurnbak (fish) were caught during their spawning season. The iilk (eels) were not harvested.[NEWLINE]
				As this chaos grew, the warreeny (sea) became angry and began to rise. The wurneet (river) became flooded and eventually the whole flat plain was covered in baany (water). It threatened to flood their whole barerarerungar (country). The people became frightened and went to Bundjil, their creator and spiritual leader. They asked Bundjil to stop the warreeny (sea) from rising.[NEWLINE]
				Bundjil was angry with his people, and he told them that they would have to change their ways if they wanted to save their land. The people thought about what they had been doing and made a promise to follow Bundjil. Bundjil walked out to the warreeny, raised his tjeera (spear) and directed the warreeny to stop rising. Bundjil then made the Boon Wurrung promise that they would respect the laws.[NEWLINE]
				The baany (water) never subsided but stayed to create a large bay that the Boon Wurrung called Nairm. Today it is known as Port Phillip Bay. The warreeny took away much of the biik (land) of the Boon Wurrung and much of their barerarerungar (country) was reduced to a narrow strip of coastline.[NEWLINE]
				The Boon Wurrung learnt from their mistakes. They returned to their old values and the laws of Bundjil. They took greater care of the biik of Bundjil and the bubup of Bundjil.
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				Waa, Fire, and the Seven Sisters[NEWLINE]Taunwurrung Country. As told by Larry Walsh
				[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				At one time, all Kulin ate their food raw and were always sick during winter. There were seven women who never complained about the cold and beautiful smells came from their camp. Waa the white Crow watched these women carefully and noticed that the tops of their digging sticks were glowing red.[NEWLINE]
				The women loved honey ants but were afraid of snakes. Waa put some baby snakes inside a hollow log and sealed it up. He told the women that there were honey ants inside and that they should use their digging sticks to break it open. All the snakes shot out and the women started hitting the ground so hard to keep the snakes away that the tops of their digging sticks broke off. Waa took off with them.[NEWLINE]
				The women called out, abusing the Crow and calling him a thief. All this noise attracted the attention of Bunjil and the women told Bunjil that Waa had stolen the secret of fire. Bunjil asked his two nephews, Jert Jert and Thara, to chase after Waa and get the sticks back. Waa flew so fast that one of the sticks caught fire and he dropped it at a place called Mooneo in the Dandenongs, the first hill burnt by fire. Thara told Jert Jert to keep going because he was a lot quicker.[NEWLINE]
				Waa then flew so fast that this time all the sticks caught fire, burning Waa and turning him black, and he landed at a place called Narnarthum in the Cathedral Ranges in Taunwurrung Country.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Kimberley Dreaming -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_NGARRANGGARNI">
			<Text>Ngarranggarni</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_NGARRANGGARNI_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				Wandjina are the supreme spirit ancestors of the Indigenous people of the Kimberley. They are found in painted form on the walls and ceilings of rock shelters in the clan estates of the Worora, Ngarinyin and Wunambal language groups, although visually similar figures can be found in Bunuba country in the central Kimberley and on Koolan Island in the Buccaneer Archipelago—traditionally part of the territory of Umiida people.[NEWLINE]
				Wandjina have names and some display individual characteristics, which identify them; however, all Wandjina share certain features that make them instantly recognisable. Their faces have eyes and nose but never a mouth. Their anthropomorphic forms are frontal and often imposing in scale, sometimes extending up to 5 metres across the walls or ceiling of shelters; however, very small examples also occur. Their heads are surrounded by a semicircular band of solid colour or radiating or dotted lines that give the impression that they are wearing a helmet or headdress.The radiating lines from the head are said to represent the lightning that foreshadows the wet season rains.Wandjina are often shown as a full body, or at least head, shoulders and torso, but some have only the head and shoulders represented. The body lacks anatomical detail and is filled with visually powerful decorative designs such as dotted and striped lines over solid pigment. An oval shape on the chest placed centrally beneath the shoulders is said to represent the ‘Wanjin’s heart, in others its breastbone, and in yet others, a pearl-shell pendant’. Most Wandjina are upright but some are depicted horizontally where they ‘lay down’ in the shelters. Some are painted in groups and others individually. Most Wandjina are drawn in outline onto a matt-white pigment background, which is created by blowing the pigment from the mouth. The outline is often in black or red and the decorative infill is applied over the white background in red, yellow, orange or black pigment. Most significantly, Wandjina are luminous and imposing, their dark eyes gazing out from their white face mesmerise, appearing to rise out from the rock surface.[NEWLINE]
				The Wandjina was intrinsically linked to the mythological life, social organisation and seasonal movements of Indigenous Kimberley peoples. Kimberley people believe that the Wandjina undertook ‘creative journeys which left the land and all living matter in its present form’. Each Indigenous group or ‘clan’ had its own territory or ‘estate’ and, following the creative journey, Wandjina ‘lay down’ in a shelter within each clan estate. ‘Each Wandjina has a name, a moiety and a set of totemic symbols from which each clan is directly descended’ and for which the members of that clan are responsible. Frequently associated with the Wandjina are myriad other motifs portraying mythological beings and a wide variety of plants, animals and items of material culture. These motifs are often linked to events that occurred in the creative journey of the Wandjina with which they are associated.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]
				From Wandjina, graffiti and heritage by Ursula Frederick and Sue O’Connor
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Uniting Church -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_UNITING_CHURCH">
			<Text>Uniting Church</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_UNITING_CHURCH_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				The Uniting Church formed on the 22nd of June 1977 when most, though not all, of the Australian congregations of the Methodist, Presbyterian, and Congregational Churches merged together under the Basis of Union. As of 2016, 870,000 people (3.7% of the population) identified as being part of the church. Although this marks a drop in around 195,000 people since 2011, this still makes them the 3rd largest denomination (Christian or otherwise) in Australia, following Catholicism and Anglicanism. Today they run such community programs as UnitingCare and Frontier Services
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Pentecostalism-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_PENTECOSTALISM">
			<Text>Pentecostalism</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RELIGION_PENTECOSTALISM_PEDIA">
			<Text>
				Pentecostalism is a Protestant movement with most of its Australian churches loosely grouped together under the Australian Christian Churches (ACC). The exact beliefs and practises can vary between congregations, but it’s mainly distinct from other Christian faiths by; its more literal approach to the Bible, its practice of speaking in tongues through baptism with the Holy Spirit, its belief in the second coming of Jesus, its belief in divine healing and other gifts, its more youthful demographic, and its more concert-like style of worship with bands, stages, singing, and raised hands in worship.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As of 2016, 1.1% of the population (around 260,000 people) identified as Pentecostal, remaining at a steady percentage since 2011 despite a drop in nearly every other Christian denomination. In 2018, Scott Morrison became Australia’s first Pentecostal Prime Minister, he attends Horizon Church (previously ShireLive) located in Sutherland, southern Sydney. Other notable churches include Hillsong in Sydney (which separated from the ACC in 2018), Planetshakers in Melbourne, Kingdomcity in Perth, and Influencers in Adelaide.
			</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>